techmynd.com 2014-06-03

# Privacy and Ads Policy - TechMynd

## Privacy Policy

We take your privacy seriously. This policy describes what [personal](http://www.techmynd.com/category/what-more/personal/ "personal") information we collect and how we use it.

## Routine Information Collection

All web servers track basic information about their visitors. This information includes, but is not limited to, IP addresses, browser details, timestamps and referring pages. None of this information can personally identify specific visitors to this site. The information is tracked for routine administration and maintenance purposes, and lets me know what pages and information are useful and helpful to visitors.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Where necessary, this site uses cookies to store information about a visitor’s preferences and history in order to better serve the visitor and/or present the visitor with customized content.

Advertising partners and other third parties may also use cookies, scripts and/or web beacons to track visitors to our site in order to display advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the third parties through their own servers and is subject to their own privacy policies.

## Controlling Your Privacy

Note that you can change your browser settings to disable cookies if you have privacy concerns. Disabling cookies for all sites is not recommended as it may interfere with your use of some sites. The best option is to disable or enable cookies on a per-site basis. Consult your browser documentation for instructions on [how to](http://www.techmynd.com/category/tips-tricks/how-to-tips-tricks/ "how to") block cookies and other tracking mechanisms.

## About Google Advertising

Any advertisements served by [Google](http://www.techmynd.com/category/internet-web/google-se/ "Google"), Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. Learn how to opt out of Google’s cookie usage. As mentioned above, any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google’s own privacy policies. Third-party advertising companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

**About Google advertising:** What is the DoubleClick DART cookie? The DoubleClick DART cookie is used by Google in the ads served on publisher websites displaying [AdSense](http://www.techmynd.com/category/internet-web/adsense/ "AdSense") for content ads. When users visit an AdSense publisher’s website and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on that end user’s browser. The data gathered from these cookies will be used to help AdSense publishers better serve and manage the ads on their site(s) and across the web. Users may [opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/). Learn more about the [DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx).

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the [Internet](http://www.techmynd.com/category/downloads/software-internet/ "Internet").
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

## Ads Networks

TechMynd serves ads mainly using services from Reduxmedia, [Valueclick Media](http://valueclickmedia.com/), [Infolinks](http://www.infolinks.com/), [buysellads](http://buysellads.com/), Adside, [Afterdownload](http://www.afterdownload.com/), [VigLink](http://www.viglink.com/?vgref=135485) ([Opt-Out from using VigLink](http://www.viglink.com/support/optout)) but not each or all. We may use any of these ads serving networks or cease to use any of these anytime. Please visit those websites if you want to know more about “how they serve ads?”, their privacy policy or terms.

Users can visit the above ad serving networks to opt out of cookies if they need. Further more we try to mention **sponsored links** or **advertisements** where possible.

## Contact Information

Concerns or questions about this privacy policy can be directed to fill in your contact information here for further clarification.

## Comments Policy

Do anybody like spam? Techmynd neither. I check every comment before it actually appears here. This is necessary to keep spammers from spoiling the content. I appreciate your patience. Relevant comments and relevant links in comments are highly encouraged. You can give your opinion in comments that how you feel about the resource which TechMynd offers you. Your emails are completely safe with TechMynd which you enter while posting comments or give while subscribing. I never sell emails or use them in any case. For this purpose Subscription methods are available. Whoever likes, can receive the TechMynd’s Newsletter and join the conversation.

## Disclaimer

At this blog you will find everything about web/software technology. If you find anything that you think must not be here then please [contact me](http://www.techmynd.com/contact/). I will remove that post/resource immediately. I try my best to post original resource and the rights of everything are reserved with their respective owners as there are links pointing towards to the origional source. I just share with my visitors this useful stuff to use and appreciate the respective origional source so please inform me if you find anything irrelevant. This blog is not by any means at commercial purposes. I do not collect information from users or visitors or never sell information and never use these for commercial purposes. I can remove anything from here without any notice or change privacy policy any time. If you do not agree with the policy then you must immediately disconnect from this website.
